我们在筹款
we're starting a fund.
那就不用我帮什么忙了
then you don't need me.
他受伤了 无法工作了
The man's injured. He can't work.
那是他自找的
His fault.
我们是一家人 必须互相依靠
We're family. We depend on each other.
我们不是一家人 只是同事而已
We're not family. We're co-workers.
他现在甚至都不算是同事了
He's not even that anymore.
真不敢相信你会这么说
I can't believe you just said that.
想让男人把酒钱掏出来谈何容易
Can't come between aabcman and his beer money.
看到那架巨大的重型机械吗?
See the big,heavy machinery?
抱歉 但他应该捐点钱
I'm sorry,but he should give.
你都捐了
You gave.
回去工作吧
Go back to work.
让你不用上晚班的正是Paolo
Paolo is the one who gotabcyou off the night shift.
又不是我叫他这么做的
It's not like I asked him.
劳动节长周末他还给你代班了
Also coved for you labor day weekend.
是没错 可这是美国啊
But hey, it's america.
如果你不想贡--
If you don'tabcwant to contribu--
if you don'tabcwant to cont--
天啊!
Oh, god!
叫救护车
Get an ambulance.
- 早上好abc- 不想听
- Good morning.abc- Don't wanna hear it.
这么说你没约Cuddy出去
So I take it you did not ask cuddy out.
是
Yeah.
"是 我没约"还是"是 我约了"?
Yeah "I didn't" or yeah "I did"?
哪一个意思是我差点听你话去约了
Whichever one means you almost hadabcme convinced it was a good idea.
- 不说点什么?abc- 不
- Nothing to say?abc- No.
"不 不想" 还是"不 我想"?
No, you don't. Or no, you don't don't?
哪一个意思是不
Whichever one means no.
你是在说反话?
Is this someabckind of reverse--
不
no.
House?
16岁女孩 有肺积水
16-year-old girl withabcfluid in her lungs.
无旧伤 无肺或心脏问题
No preous auma, lung, or cardiac issues.
革兰氏染色剂阴性反应
Gram stain was negative.
无细菌 无肺炎
No bacteria, no pneumonia.
她在工厂工作
She's a factory worker.
意味着她可能接触到许多国外移民
Means she probably works closeabcto a lot of recent immigrants.
感谢上帝 一些血汗工厂abc远渡重洋重归美国怀抱
Thank god some of those offshore sweatabcshop jobs are coming back to america.
她是法律授予独立行为能力的未成年人
She's an emancipated minor.
在工厂?
In a factory?
要不是摔断腿的奥运体操运动员
Either an olympic gymnastabcwho busted her leg,
就是把续集赚的钱都花在吸毒上的童星
a child star who blew allabcher sequel money on drugs,
要么就是离家出走的小孩在撒谎
or she's just a lying runaway.
她父母去年去世了
Her parents died last year.
没有任何亲人
No relatives.
不想被寄养 她拿了普教水平证abc批准成为独立行为能力人
To avoid foster care, she gotabca G.E.D. And got emancipated.
可能在同事那传染了寄生虫
Could have picked up aabcparasite from a co-worker.
可能有肠胃毛病
She'd be having G.I.Problems.
最有可能就是怀孕了
Pregnancy's more likely.
导致液体超载 冲击肺部 引起肺水肿
Sparks a fluid overload, hits theabclungs, causes the pulmonary edema.
她的病史说最近没有性生活
Her history says she'sabcnot sexually active.
而据我们经验她可能撒谎了
And our history says she could be lying.
不是所有十几岁年轻人都在上床的
But not every teenager is having sex.
但所有十几岁年轻人都很蠢
But every teenager is stupid.
无人监管使他们更蠢
Teenagers on their own are stupider.
那女孩能保住工作 付房租
The girl's holding downabca job, makes her rent.
一方面 Kutner是对的
On the one hand, kutner's right.
也许她是个甜蜜的小东西abc不是个爱撒谎的烂人
Maybe she's a sweet young thing, notabca screw-up lying through her teeth.
另一方面 验孕只需要5分钟abc而且现在不需杀兔子提血清制验孕剂了
On the two hand, a pregnancy test only takesabcfive minutes, and we no longer kill rabbits.
总而言之 闭嘴 做测试
So in conclusion, shut up, do the tests.
还有什么?
What else?
吸毒可使心脏受损
Drugs could damage the heart.
体压不平衡会使肺部积水
Pressure imbalance allowsabcfluid to build up in the lungs.
毒检结果是干净的
Tox screen's clean.
只能检出最近有否吸毒
For drugs used recently.
无法检出以前的吸毒情况
Not for drugs used before recently.
不是16岁就意味着放浪形骸的
16 doesn't automaticallyabcmean a risky lifestyle.
刚才不是聊过这话题吗?
didn't we just have this conversation?
Kutner相信她 有人不相信
Kutner trusts her. Someone else doesn't.
言而总之 闭嘴
So, in conclusion, shut up.
去她家和工作的地方查看有无毒品
Check her home and workabcfor toxins or drugs.
Kutner和Foreman做个超声波
Kutner and foreman, do an echo.
查查心脏损伤的的程度
Find the extent of the heart damage.
Kutner能独立完成超声波
Kutner can do the echo on his own.
没错...
Yes...
但这样就很寂寞了
but he'll be very lonely.
我是不是要问为什么?
So I have to ask why?
有人叫我帮忙进行临床实验
I've been asked to helpabcrun a clinical trial.
你同意吗?
That okay with you?
对你的职业生涯有助益
Good for your career.
对道上信誉有助益
Great for your street cred.
那对我有什么好处呢?
What's in it for me?
你有四个医生 永远不超过一个案子
You have four doctors andabcnever more than one case.
意味着我有时间干点别的
It means I have timeabcto work on other things.
这样他们也有机会进步
And they'll have moreabcchances to step up.
独立成长
Stand on their own.
那要是Annie出状况了abc是不是要等你给小白鼠刷完毛啊?
And if there's an emergency with annie, shouldabcshe wait until you finish grooming lab rats?
要是Sophia或其他病人出问题了abc你知道我会到的
If there's a problem with sophia or anyabcother patient, you know I'll be there.
病人优先
The patient is my priority.
不准去
No.
噢 还要我给个理由吗?
Oh, do you want a reason?
临床实验很费时 你的时间就是我的时间
Clinical trials takeabctime. Your time is my time.
我说过我不吸毒
I told you, I don't do drugs.
那检查一下心脏也好
Still a good idea to check your heart.
还有别的原因会使心脏受损
Something else could have damaged it.
什么都靠自己挺难的吧?
You find it hard being all on your own?
自力更生 没有--
Having to doabceverything without--
吸毒来减轻痛苦?
drugs to ease my pain?
- 我不是那个意--abc- 十几岁的年轻人独自为生?
- That's not what--abc- teenager on her own?
换了我也不会信任的
I wouldn't trust me either.
我意思是一定很艰难
I meant it must be hard.
没有依靠
No one there to back you up.
我知道你是好意 但我对怜悯没兴趣
I know you're trying to be nice, butabcI'm not into the whole pity thing.
不是怜悯 是理解
I was actually doingabcthe "I get it" thing.
我六岁时 父母双亡了
I lost my parents when I was six.
伤心的感觉永远不会消失
It doesn't go away.
但慢慢会好过些
But it gets easier.
你会学会怎么处理
You learn to deal.
听到敲门声时我依然会紧张
I still get nervous whenabcthere's a knock on the door.
总觉得门外的是州警...
Always think it's the state trooper...
带来更多的噩耗
with more bad news.
你已经历了最糟的事 并挺过来了
You already got theabcworst news and survived.
算是好的一面了
That's sorta the upside.
你的心脏很健康
Your heart's healthy.
难道不是好事吗?
Isn't that good news?
对心脏来说是好事
For your heart, yeah.
但也意味着我们仍不知道问题出在哪
But it also means weabcstill don't know what's wrong.
收支平衡 住处洁净
Checkbook balanced,place spotless.
家具都是自己打的
Looks like she builds her own furniture.
16岁就这样了 30岁会变成什么样?
If you're this grown upabcat 16,what happens at 30?
会童心未泯 越活越回去
You turn back into a kid.
像Kutner一样
Like kutner.
Kutner也没那么糟
Kutner's not that bad.
他要求万物得要和谐美好
He needs everything to be nice.
要看到所有人善良一面
He wants to see the best in everyone.
厨房也没问题
Kitchen's clear.
是啊 待人友好很危险啊
Yeah, friendly isa dangerous thing.
过度信任你听说过没有?
There is such a thing as too trusting.
引伸出信任不足也是个问题
Corollary is there is such aabcthing as not trusting enough.
太多 会受伤
Too much, you get hurt.
太少 活不下去
Not enough, you don't live.
那么人生目标就是适当受点伤?
So the object in life is toabcget hurt just the right amount?
原谅我无法从你那接受与人交往的建议
Excuse me if I don't goout of my wayabcto take relationship advice from you.
而信任...
And trust...
得自己争取
should be earned.
水烟枪代表不了什么abc跟吸毒无关
Bong means nothing.abcDrugs are irrelevant.
如果她确实吸了就有关了
Relevant if she's taking them.
即使真吸了 还是无关
Even if she is:Irrelevant.
超声波显示心脏无损伤
Echo showed no heart damage.
是那个被我毁了发明新药之梦的
Would that be the echo thatabcforeman chose not to run with you
Foreman没跟你一起做超声波吗
after I dashed hisnewabcdrug discovery dreams?
你因为Kutner搞砸了超声波abc而生我的气?
You mad at me because youabcthink kutner screwed up the echo?
我可没有搞砸超声波
I didn't screw up the echo.
我知道
I know.
心脏结构无损坏
No structural heart damage.
那如果不是心脏问题...
So if it's not the heart...
是心脏问题
it's the heart.
那你刚才又说不是?
Didn't you just say it's not?
不是所有心脏问题都是结构受损的
Not all heart damage hasabcto be structural.
毒品会导致间歇性心动过速
Drugs could haveabccaused intermittent tachycardia.
心跳不规则能导致肺水肿
Irregular heart beat would accountabcfor the pulmonary edema.
水肿是急性的
The edema was acute.
血管炎更说得通
Vasculitis makes more sense.
验血无血管炎迹象
There's no sign in her blood work.
要患了血管炎abc她会虚弱得无法在工厂上班
And if she had vasculitis, she'dabcbe too weak to work in a factory.
她连家具都能自己打
She builds her own furniture.
会因为身体些许不适而翘班?
You think she skips work becauseabcshe's feeling a little weak?
她需要类固醇
She needs steroids.
类固醇会引起心跳不规则abc这样她的心条就更更更不规则了
Steroids could cause an irregular heartbeat,abcmaking her current one irregular-er-er.
Foreman给她用β-受体阻滞药
Foreman. Start her on beta-blockers.
其他人干点别的啥 就是不准帮忙
The rest of you, do anything thatabcisn't starting her on beta-blockers.
给她用药 需要我就呼我
Start her on the treatment.abcPage me if you need me.
心跳不规则会使血液回流abc到心脏之后 流入肺部
Irregular heartbeat causes blood to backabcup behind the heart and into the lungs.
β-受体阻滞药能阻止此事发生
The beta-blockers keepabcthis from happening.
上次测试不是说我心脏没事吗
I thought the testabcshowed my heart was fine.
心律不齐很狡猾 是间歇性的
It's tricky. Anabcarrhythmia can come and go.
这么说你既不相信我也不相信测试结果
So you don't believe me or the test.
你们这些人比我还愤世嫉俗
You guys are more cynical than I am.
我们在你家里找到了水烟枪
We found the bong in your apartment.
你们还进了我房子?
You went into my apartment?
长期吸毒会损伤--
Extended drugabcuse can damage--
烟枪是我前男友的abc正因为这样才把他甩了
the bong belongs to myabcex. It's why he's ex.
不代表你没用过
That doesn't mean you didn't use it.
不
No.
你没有理由相信我
You have no reason to trust me.
你必须得按规定给我治疗
You have to do your treatment.
还有一个可能是你患了血管炎
The other possibilityabcis you have vasculitis.
可用类固醇治疗
The treatment for that is steroids.
但要是你有在吸毒 心脏受损abc类固醇会使你丧命的
If you've been using drugs,if they've damaged yourabcheart and I start you on steroids, they could kill you.
我没有吸毒
I haven't used drugs.
我去拿类固醇
I'll get the steroids.
你为什么会在这?
Why are you here?
- 还欠着门诊值班abc- 不 你没有
- I owe clinic hours.abc- No, you don't.
是因为House不想我在这
I'm here because house doesn'tabcwant me to be here.
他拒绝放你去搞临床试验?
I'm guessing he saidabcno to the clinical trials.
他不需要我的
He didn't need to say no.
只因为想说拒绝而拒绝
He just wanted to say no.
House做事只为了私利?
House did somethingabcsolely out of self-interest?
让人毛骨悚然呢
That's freaky.
- 不认为你会越级批准我?abc- 不会
- Don't suppose you'd want to override?abc- No.
你这样做想证明些什么?
What do you think this is gonna prove?
有什么关系?
Does it matter?
觉得你这可能需要些帮手而已
Just figured you couldabcuse some help down here.
而你花两小时帮人擦鼻涕abc能惹恼House
And you spending two hours wipingabcnoses will annoy house.
如果这就是你的梦想 祝你好运
If that is your dream,god bless.
但想证明你能完成他的工作外abc还做点别的...
If you want to prove you can doabchis job and something more...
他的呕吐物是红色的
his puke is red.
是血 对吗?
That's blood, right?
痛不痛?
That hurt?
这样呢?
What about that?
他这样已经四天了 越来越糟
Four days he's been likeabcthis. It's just getting worse.
也许拉出来就好了
Maybe he just needs to poop.
- Evan!abc- 怎么了?
- Evan!abc- What?
我上次肚子疼时就有效啊
Worked last time I had a stomach ache.
事实上是个好主意
It's actually a smart idea.
所以其他医生首先就检查这项了
Which is why that'sthe firstabcthing the other doctors checked.
里面没东西
His insides are clear.
- 托儿所还有其他人得病吗?abc- 没有
- Anyone else sick in daycare?abc- No.
- 他的朋友呢?abc- 没有
- How 'bout his friends?abc- No. No one.
- 他得什么病了?abc- 还不能确定
- What's happening to him?abc- Not sure yet.
别担心 我有个想法
Don't worry. I've got an idea.
你会让他好起来的 对吗?
You can make him better, right?
正打算这么做
That's my plan.
你必须得让他好起来
You need to make him better.
离我远点!
Stay the hell away from me!
冷静
just calm down.
怎么了?
What happened?
给她调节静脉注射器 她就发狂了
I adjusted her iv, and she went crazy.
别碰我! 离我远点!
Don't touch me! Leave me alone!
- Sophia没事的 我们是来帮你的abc- 离我远点!
- Sophia, it's okay. We're here to help you.abc- just stay away from me!
别碰我!
Don't touch me!
别--
I said,abcdon't--
放手!放手--
get your hands offabcof me! Get your hands--
β-受体阻滞药不会引致精神崩溃
beta-blockers don'tabccause psychotic breaks.
她没用β-受体阻滞药
She's not on beta-blockers.
我们给她用了强安定药 稳定下来了
we started her onabchaloperidol. She's stable.
测试结果说明精神狂乱不是因为代谢问题
Lab tests showed the delirium wasn'tabccaused by a metabolic problem.
意味着我们仍不知是什么引致的
Means we still don'tabcknow what caused it.
没错 干得好 Foreman.
Yeah, we do. Niceob, foreman.
不是我换了她的药的
I didn't switch her meds.
但你放手让一个同情心泛滥的人去干这活
But your decision to stick it to theabcman clearly inspired oliver twist.
我根据她表现出的症状治疗
I treated her based on theabcsymptoms she presented.
你根据同情孤儿症治疗abc还差点把她害死
You treated her based on empathetic orphanabcsyndrome, and almost killed her in the process.
她用类固醇的时间不至于引起狂乱abc--这是个新症状
She wasn't on steroids long enough for itabcto cause the delirium--it's a new symptom.
把血管炎排除掉的新症状
One that rules out vasculitis.
也排除了心率不齐abc精神崩溃激发肾上腺素
And arrhytia. The psychoticabcbreak caused a surge of adrenaline,
但并无心跳不规则现象abc心脏没问题 我们都错了
but no irregular heartbeat. Heart'sabcnot the problem. We're both wrong.
那是什么引起肺部问题和精神狂乱?
So what causes lung issues and delirium?
不能想当然地以为她健康又快乐?
And is not based on wishfulabcthinking that she's safe and happy?
变异型心绞痛
Prinzmetal angina.
闷闷不乐比多嘴却帮不上忙好
Silent and unhappy isabcbetter than vocal and unhelpful.
要是你做了你没做的超声波abc用了你没用的β-受体阻滞药
If you'd run the echo that you didn't run beforeabcgiving her the beta-blockers that you didn't give her--
听了Kutner刚刚说的话abc就会知道这不是心脏问题
if you'd listened to what kutner justabcsaid, you'd know it's not a heart problem.
我不是说她的心脏
I'm not talking about her heart.
是说她的脑
I'm talking about her head.
变异型心绞痛不会影响--
Prinzmetalabcangina doesn't affect--
这可能会引发大脑血管痉挛
no reason it couldn't cause anabcartery in the brain to spasm.
导致精神错乱及肺水肿
Leads to the delirium andabcthe pulmonary edema.
Foreman 让她用麦角新碱 引发血管痉挛abc然后做功能性磁共振 看哪根血管抽风了
Foreman, give her ergonovine to cause vasospasms,abcand run an fmri to see which artery's dancing.
还有 当我说Foreman时abc我指的是...Foreman
And when I say foreman,Iabcmean... foreman.
我要他在文件上签名abc我要录像作实
I want his signature on theabcpaperwork. I want videotape.
我要他拿着今天的报纸和病人合影
I want photographs of him withabcthe patient and today's newspaper.
行动吧 等你们准备好--
Set her up.Whenabcyou're ready--
- House要你--abc- 走程序
- house wants you--abc- to do the procedure.
当一切准备就绪 呼我
When you get everything set up,page me.
这真是摄相机吗?
That's really a camera?
很酷吧?
Pretty cool, huh?
它能拍摄其他镜头照不到的地方
This can go places theabcother scopes can'T.
Jonah 我要你把这颗药丸吞了
Jonah, I need you to swallow this pill.
我不要
Don't wanna.
不痛的 我保证
It doesn't hurt. Promise.
Jonah 求你了
Jonah, please.
这会让你好起来
To help make you better.
我不想当坏叔叔 但你不肯的话abc我们只好硬来咯
I don't want to be mean, but if youabcdon't do this,we'll have to make you.
这是能量丸 不只是相机
it's a power pill. It's not ust a camera.
会让你的肌肉变强壮
It makes your muscles grow.
和我们吃的维他命一样
Like the vitamins we take.
但这是秘方炮制的
Except this was made withabca secret formula.
你做得很好 甜心 你很勇敢
You did great, sweetheart.abcYou're very brave.
Jonah很幸运
jonah's lucky.
我在你这年纪 对我弟弟可凶了
I was pretty cruel to my littleabcbrother when I was your age.
为什么?
Why?
我以为当哥哥就得这样
I guess I thought that'sabcwhat big brothers did.
显然我错了
Obviously, I was wrong.
他也是医生吗?
Is he a doctor too?
不是
No.
吞了药丸会痒吗 宝贝?
Does the pill tickle,sweetie?
他不会有感觉abc你笑什么 你哥哥?
he can't feel it. What'sabcfunny, your brother?
- 怎么回事?abc- 我不知道
- What's happening?abc- I don't know.
你们最近关系怎么样?
How you guys getting along?
你为什么突然关心这个了?
And you suddenly care why?
House上星期问起你们
House was asking questions last week.
我猜Foreman需要我们帮忙abc又担心我俩在闹别扭 会分了神
I assume foreman needs us, and he's worried thatabcif we're sniping, we might be distracted.
- 这也太瞧不起人了 对吧?abc- 非常
- That's kind of insulting, isn't it?abc- Very.
显然你们好得很
You're obviously fine.
我要为一个笑个不停的病人作鉴别诊断
I need a differential forabcuncontrollable giggling.
他才4岁 小孩子爱笑
He's four. They laugh.
没错
Yeah.
腹泻和吐血不会让人有心思傻笑
Nothing like diarrhea and bloody vomitabcto put you in the mood to goof around.
我把他从头到脚检查了一遍
I've looked down oneabcend and up the other.
所有结果都显示没有问题
All the tests came back clean.
我实在找不出原因
I can't figure this out.
找不到? 你共事的不是还有abc三位医生和一个瘸子愤青吗?
You can't? Don't you work with threeabcother doctors and a grouchy gimp?
这不是House的病例
This isn't house's case.
你知道的 无论你想证明什么abc都只是徒劳无功
Just so you know,whatever you'reabctrying to prove, it won't be enough.
得走了
Gotta go.
- 对不起abc- 你没有错过什么 痉挛还没发作
sorry. You didn't missabcmuch. No spasms yet.
大脑前动脉和后动脉都没有异样
Nothing in the anterior orabcposterior cerebral arteries.
还有多久?
How much longer?
还有几分钟就好
Just a few more minutes.
收养你的家庭住这附近abc还是你得转学?
Were your foster homes all around here,abcor did you have to change schools?
谈论糟糕的养父母有助使我放松吗?
Is chatting about lousy fosterabcparents supposed to relax me?
左中动脉看来没问题
Left middle cerebral artery looks good.
我的养父母人很好
My foster parents were great.
我想 大部分人收养孩子abc是因为他们想做件好事
I think most foster parents do itabcbecause they want to do something decent.
所以你没去要求独立生活许可
Which is why you didn't get emancipated.
椎动脉附近没有异样
Nothing around the vertebral artery.
没有痉挛迹象
No sign of spasms.
但这很奇怪
But that's odd.
你如何得知父母的死讯?
How'd you find out about your parents?
我说过了 州警说的
I told you. State trooper.
你看这里
Look at that.
动脉没问题 你可以停了
Arteries are fine. You can stop.
不是这里
Not that.
我忘了 是他去你家abc还是把你叫到警察局?
I forget,did he come to your houseabcor call you down to the station?
他来我家
came to my house.
我伏在那人身上哭了一小时
I cried into the guy's shirt for an hour.
功能性磁共振能指出血液流向哪里
Fmris tell us where the blood flow is.
你在用大脑的边缘部分思考
You were using your limbic region.
当我们运用想象力时abc这部分会被点亮
It lights up when we use our imagination.
当我们说真话时 它不会被点亮
It doesn't lig up whenabcwe're telling the truth.
你的父母没死 对吧?
Your parents aren't dead,are they?
我冒着丢饭碗的危险abc让你用另一种疗法--
I risked my job, put you onabca different treatment--
磕药的事我没撒谎
I didn't lie about the drugs.
那你为什么谎称父母死了?
Then why lie about your parents?
因为我宁愿他们已经死了
Because i wish they were dead.
这样我才要求独立生活abc因为我爸爸强暴了我
I got emancipated becauseabcmy dad raped me.
我妈却装作没事发生
And my mom pretended it didn't happen.
没有痉挛 没有血流障碍abc也没有脑功能紊乱
no signs of spasm, impededabcblood flow, or brain dysfunction.
不是变异型心绞痛
It's not prinzmetals.
功能性磁共振的结果abc证明House是对的
All the fmri showed is house was right.
她在撒谎
She was lying.
没有意义 除非是撒谎abc引起了肺水肿和精神错乱
Only relevant if it canabccause pulmonary edema and delirium.
知道病人被强暴了abc你只有这点反应?
We find out our patient's beenabcraped, and that's your response?
我们是心理医生么?
Is she a psych patient?
强暴可能导致性病
Rape could mean std.
感谢上帝 你们当中总算有个没心没肺的
Thank goodness one ofabcyou doesn't have a heart.
别在这上面纠结abc也许我们能解决问题
Maybe if we all stopped wringingabcour hands, we could solve this thing
让她哪怕是噩梦般的人生得以延续
and let her live toabchave a few more nightmares.
淋球菌心内膜炎可以解释abc肺水肿和精神错乱
Gonococcal endocarditis would explainabcthe pulmonary edema,the delirium.
血液测试无此迹象
No sign in her bloodwork.
强暴的事可能也是撒谎
Could be lying about the rape.
昨天你还是她的贴心小棉袄
Yesterday,you were all bff.
现在却认定她是大话精了?
Now you think she's pathological.
昨天我没理由怀疑她
Yesterday I had no reason to doubt her.
如果她一开始肯说实话--
If she'd been honest withabcus from the beginning--
她撒谎是因为父母死了abc总比他们是强奸犯好
she lied about dead parents becauseabcit's better than rapist parents.
难道这不值得同情吗?
You find that unsympathetic?
- 这就对了abc- 什么对了?
- that's it.abc- What's it?
她的一生都很不堪
Her whole life's a mess.
哪个词和"不堪"押韵?
What rhymes with mess?
不可能是"负担"
It's not stress.
她没有任何反常表现abc荷尔蒙分泌正常 没有心脏--
She has none of the usual anifestations.Noabchormone imbalance,no cardiac--
没错 她差点让自己的肺给呛死abc而且精神病发作
yeah, she's drowning in herabcown lungs, and she's delirious.
她的情绪真是稳如泰山那
She's a picture of emotional health.
严重的精神负担可能abc导致中脑运作不平衡
Severe emotional stress can leadabcto asymmetric funion of the midbrain.
解释了精神错乱
Explains the delirium.
大脑和心脏的联系被干扰导致肺水肿
Interruption of the brain-heartabccoupling could cause pulmonary edema.
即使House错了 用的也无非是abc普通抗忧郁药物 没什么争议
Even if house is wrong,the treatment'sabcbasic all anti-anxiety meds. Hard to argue with.
对 我赞同意 这的确解释了一切
Yes. I agree. It doesabcexplain everything.
13 去给她服用安定
Thirteen, load her upon diazepam.
Foreman 去盯着她
Foreman, make sure she does it.
13 去盯着他盯着你
Thirteen, make sure he makes sure.
我去了Cuddy家
I went to cuddy's house.
但我没进去
But I didn't go in.
打道回府 既没有轻叩柴扉abc也没有叩开心扉
Went home without ringing eitherabcher metaphoricalor actual bell.
你在敷衍
You're processing.
我在消毒
I'm scrubbing.
"哼"表示你在敷衍
"Huh" means processing.
"哼"表示我听到了
"Huh" means acknowledging.
你喜欢的话 我可以换"哈"或"嗯"或--
If you prefer, I couldabcsay"ha," or "hmm," or--
没有循循善诱? 没有真知灼见?abc你一定很失望
no insights? No opinions?abcYou're disappointed.
你已经作了决定
You made the decision.
我不能告诉你什么是对的
I can't tell you what's right for you.
是吗?
Seriously?
但是你上星期可以
'Cause last week you could.
去年也可以
Last year you could.
对你可谓驾轻就熟
Seems to come pretty easy to you.
你要我告诉你怎么做?
Do you want me to tellabcyou what you should do?
我要你别再故作深沉了abc这会让人很抓狂
I want you to stop thinking that actingabcinscrutable makes you anything other than annoying.
好玩
Interesting.
成天憋着会让你得癌症的!
Holding things in can give you cancer!
孩子在接受护理 可能是脑膜炎
Kid's in daycare. Could be meningitis.
没有发烧 没有四肢僵硬 没有皮疹
No fever,no stiffness, no rash.
甲状腺查了没?
You check his thyroid?
促甲状腺激素和甲状腺素全部正常
Tsh and 3 t4 were within range.
排除了所有常规疾病
Ruled out all the usual suspects.
对4岁的孩子来说 什么病都不常规abc可笑的是 我们似乎成了你的帮凶
Nothing's usual for a four-year-old, and asabcfun as this is,it feels like we're your goomah.
你觉得我们做错了?
Your feelings are hurt?
你要么两边都能搞定 要么都搞不定
Eitherou can handle bothabcthese cases or you can't.
要是你做不到 两边跨刀做既危险又愚蠢
If you can't,it's dangerous and stupid.
换个话题说 胃癌
On the other hand, stomach cancer.
平滑肌肉瘤
Leiomyosarcoma.
不靠谱
Long shot.
精神状态发生变化abc卟啉症可能性更大
Altered mental statusabcmeans porphyria's more likely.
没有腹痛
No abdominal pain?
癌症解释了情绪失常abc胃肠道症状--
Cancer explains theabclethargy, the gi symptoms--
两者都不能完全符合
neither's perfect.
我们两个测试都做
Then we test for both.
是"我们" 你就别掺乎了
And by "we," you mean theabccollective "not you."
谢谢
Thanks.
严重的精神压力扰乱了abc大脑和其它器官的联系
Severe stress scrambles the way the brainabccommunicates with the rest of the body.
我的脑子有问题?
I have a problem with my brain?
不完全是
Not exactly.
问题和你身体的化学平衡有关
The problem would be withabcyour body chemistry.
Kutner医生呢?
Where's dr. Kutner?
我们4个共同负责 现在轮到我
There's four of us. It's my turn.
对不起我欺骗了你们
I'm sorry I lied about my parents.
你这么做只是为了保护你自己
You did what you thought youabchad to do to protect yourself.
如果我们是对的 你的肺会很快好转
If we're right,we should see aabcchange in your lungs pretty fast.
我们也会找出处理压力的方法
Then we can figure outabchow to manage your stress.
去告发他也许有帮助
it might help to turn him in.
向警方报案 了结这件事
File a police report,get closure.
没用的
Won't help.
逃避并不能使你解脱
Not addressing whatabchappened won't make it go away.
是吗?
Yeah?
那我怎么做才能解脱?
What do I have to doto make it go away?
我不是这意思 我的意思是--
I didn't mean that.Iabcjust mean that you--
我正视这问题 我摆脱了那个人
I addressed it. I got away from him.
报警只会使我被贴上标签
Reporting it just labels me.
"被爸爸强奸的女孩"
"Girl raped by dad."
没人会这么看你的
it doesn't have to define you.
你是这么看我的
It's how you see me.
所以你们给我注射镇定剂
That's why you're treatingabcme with tranquilizers.
不必了
Not anymore.
精神负担不会使尿液变色
Stress wouldn't change your urine color.
检测结果显示abc褐色尿液由红血球破裂导致
Labs show the brown urine wasabccaused by shredded red cells.
到底是什么搞垮了她的肺 她的脑子abc还在她的血液里开电锯?
So what messes with her lungs,her mentalabcstatus, and runs her blood through a wood chipper?
工厂午餐间干净不到哪里去abc可能会有大肠杆菌
factory lunch rooms aren't the cleanestabcplaces. Coulda picked up E. Coli.
或是厕所里有志贺氏菌abc两者均会导致红血球破裂 精神错乱
Or shigella from the restroom. Either wouldabcaccount for the red cells, the delirium.
但不会引起开头的肺部病状
But not the original lung symptoms.
军团病能 还会引发精神错乱
Legionnaire's could,and cause delirium.
不 血钠水平正常
No, her sodium's normal.
她家的家具长什么样?
What does her furniture look like?
手工自制 旧箱拼凑 还是别的?
Said it was homemade. Old boxes, what?
就是把木头钉在一块儿
It was wood nailed together.
木头上有没有裂纹或者洞洞?
The wood have little dents or holes?
书架上没发现 但上面髹了油漆
I didn't see any in theabcbookshelves, but they were painted.
书桌上有
the desk did.
似乎她把很多东西钉在了上面
Looked like she hadabcstapled stuff all over it.
洞洞意味木料经过加压处理
holes means that itabcwas pressure-treated.
锯切和燃烧使之释放砷abc并被她吸入肺部
Sawing or burning releases arsenicabcinto the air. Into her lungs.
测试没有显示--
Testsabcdidn't show--
因为它披上了隐形斗篷--
because it found a cloak ofabcinvisibility hiding--
砷被内脏吸收了abc血液测试发现不了
arsenic gets absorbed in the internal organsabcso it doesn't show up in the blood tests.
检测她的头发
Test her hair.
如果呈阳性 用螯合疗法将其排出血液
If it's positive,chelateabcit out of her blood.
不是癌症 不是卟啉症
no cancer, no porphyria.
你把我找来就为了看阴性结果?
You paged me with negative test results?
是的 这意味着我们无能为力了
Yes, because it means we're done.
我们找不出病因 这孩子问题大了
Since we still don't know what'sabcwrong, this kid has a real problem.
和House说了没?
Talk to house?
这不是他的病例
Not his case.
某个点是我和Cameron无法企及的
There's a point whenabccameron and I aren't enough.
我们还没到那点
We're not there.
我们要做进一步检测
We need to run some more tests.
一星期前 他还是个成天和abc他哥哥玩耍的快乐小男孩
A week ago, he was a happy littleabcboy playing with his brother,
现在却连头都抬不起来了
and now he can barely lift his head.
我们会找出病因 我只要--
We'll figure thisabcout. I just need--
妈!救命!
mom! Help!
叫急救车来!
We need a crash cart!
- 出什么事了?abc- 他的心跳停止了
- What's going on?abc- He's in cardiac arrest.
让他们出去
Get them outta here.
让开
Clear.
没反应 再来
Nothing. Go again.
让开
Clear.
心跳恢复了
He's back.
Foreman 我们到那点了
foreman. We're there.
螯合治疗大功告成
Chelation's complete.
你体内的砷已被清除
You're arsenic-free.
那我可以出院了?
So I can get outta here?
明天一早
In the morning.
就这样了?
That's it?
没有建议?
No advice?
不警告我"以后小心 孩子"?
No "be careful out there, kiddo?"
你想听我的建议?
You want my advice?
虽然我不想 但我料想你会说
Want is one thing,expect's another.
我也希望能告诉你怎么做
I wish I could tell you what to do.
但你很坚强
But you're strong.
你作出了正确的抉择
You've make good choices.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
拿4毫克劳拉西泮来!
Need four milligrams lorazepam!
痉挛过后 我们重做了核磁共振
after the seizure, we ran a new mri.
这是Sophia三天前的脑子abc这是今天的
This is sophia's brain three daysabcago, this is her brain today.
脑损伤
lesions.
离奇的损伤abc不知从哪冒出来了
Magical lesions,whichabcappear out of nowhere.
她先是被治好了 接着又不行了
She was cured,then she wasn't.
速度比癌症的损伤快
Lesions grew too fast for cancer.
可能是感染 耐甲氧西林金葡菌
Could be infection. Mrsa.
那她的白细胞计数得高过天花板了
Wbc count would be through the roof.
把砷弄回去
Put the arsenic back.
你要对一个几乎被毒死的病人继续下毒?
you wanna treat a patient nearly poisonedabcto death by giving her more poison?
某物虽被称之为毒药abc但并非一定对你有害
Just because we call something aabcpoison doesn't mean it's bad for you.
砷差点没害死她
It was killing her.
但她现在还是快死了abc可见砷不是罪魁祸首
But since she's still dying, theabcarsenic obviously wasn't killing her.
她现在情况更糟 说明砷能救她的命
And since she's now getting worse, theabcarsenic was obviously fighting the killer.
英雄事迹啊
It's a hero.
可得好好宣扬一下
We should be organizing a parade.
那砷能治什么?
So what does arsenic treat?
梅毒 有青霉素前 都是用砷治
Syphilis. Before penicillin,abcthe treatment was arsenic.
已经排除了性病的可能 就算是
We already ruled out stds,andabceven if we were wrong,
那么多砷 也早该杀光她体内的梅毒了
that much arsenic in her systemabcwould've wiped out the syphilis.
急性早幼粒细胞白血病也能用砷治
Acute promyelocytic leukemia's stillabctreated with arsenic.
急性早幼粒细胞白血病可以解释abc除去砷之后的器官损伤
Apl explains the lesions and why theyabcappeared after we took the arsenic out.
那就再用回砷
So, put the arsenic back.
还是有个问题
We still have a problem.
砷只能拖延白血病 无法根治
Arsenic slows leukemia,butabcit can't cure it.
要想活到17岁 她得接受骨髓移植
If she wants to see 17, she'sabcgonna need a bone marrow transplant.
兄弟姐妹或父母是最佳供体
Best match would be aabcsibling or a parent.
活检脑部损伤 确定她要死了abc再给她上满砷
Biopsy a lesion,confirm that she'sabcdying, then load her up with arsenic.
确保她活着 直到说服她 强奸犯的骨髓
Keep her alive till youabccan convince her that rapist marrow
和纵容强奸犯的骨髓一样管用
and rapist-enabling marrow workabcjust as well as the unleaded stuff.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
是关于你瞒着我的那个孩子 病例?
This about the case you didn'tabcwant me to know about?
- Cuddy告诉你的?abc- 是Foreman你自己
- Cuddy?abc- Foreman.
一个16岁的病人几天之内就要死了abc你却没有犹豫
You didn't flinch when you found out about aabcsixteen-year-old who could be dying in the next few days.
说明你手头有个年龄更小abc死得更快的病人
Means you're here about someone evenabcyounger dying even faster.
他需要你
He needs you.
但他已经有你了啊
But he has you.
这孩子就快死了
This boy is going to die.
你就这么自私 不顾他死活?
You selfish enough to let it happen?
锅子还笑壶太黑?
Pot calling a kettle a pot?
你是个伪君子
You're a hypocrite.
我们的工作就是查出病因abc你理应救这孩子
If our job is to find out what'sabckilling patients, you'd help this kid.
但你就爱玩心理战 好像谁都没你厉害
But you'd rather play mind games to proveabcyou're the only one with magical powers.
你不是想单干么?
Wanted something all your own?
去啊
Now you got it.
我不会善罢甘休的
Your disengagement won't work.
看得出来
I can see that.
你以为你告诉我该做什么abc我就会本能地反抗
You think that when you tell me what Iabcshould do, my instincts are to push back,
所以要是你什么都不说abc我就会照你的想法去做
so that by not telling me what you think Iabcshould do, I'll do what you thinkI should do.
我咋这么爱绕呢
I sound convoluted.
走为上计既不巧妙 也不奏效
Disengagement isabcneither artful nor effective.
所以 要是我不行动abc你也就什么都不做?
So my not doing anythingabcisn't causing you to do anything?
没错
Right.
我无所谓
I'm okay with that.
不 你才不是呢
No, you're not.
你生来就有主见 还爱强迫别人接受
You are designed to have opinionsabcand to force them on people.
听上去真绝望
I'm starting to sound desperate.
别乱动我的东西
Don't screw with my stuff.
我只需要个血型一致的供体 是么?
I just need a donor with the sameabcblood type or something, right?
事实上 骨髓更复杂一些
Actually, bone marrow'saabclittle more complex.
最佳供体是直系亲属
The best donors are immediate family.
但骨髓库里有好多捐赠者呢
But those donor banks haveabcthousands of names.
- 父母DNA的匹配可能性更大...abc- 不行
- Your parents' similar dna givesabcyou a much better chan-- - no.
要是这么做 我这辈子都欠他们
If I do this, I'll owe my life to them.
就意味着从前的一切都无可厚非
It'd mean everything elseabcthat had happened was somehow okay.
他们不配
They don't deserve that.
我的生命中不需要他们
They're not in my life.
如果这意味着死亡 那就让我去死
If that means I'm dead,then I'm dead.
我有亨廷顿舞蹈症
I have huntington's disease.
我要死了
I'm dying.
不知道具体时间 但比我预想的快
Don't know when it'll happen, butabcit'll be sooner than I ever planned.
而我会尽量拖延时间
And I'd do anything to stop it.
因为唯一正确的选择
Because the only wayabcto mak anything right,
唯一让生命有意义的方法abc就是尽你所能
the only way to make yourabclife matter is to live as long
活得长久 活得精彩
and as well as you possibly can.
你被强奸过么?
Have you ever been raped?
没有
No.
别假装你了解我的心情abc我对你的感觉没兴趣
Don't try to walkin my shoesabcand I won't try to walk in yours.
你没这权利
You had no right.
试图说服她做正确的事?
To try to convinceabcher to do the right thing?
对她撒谎
To lie to her.
故事是真的 谁在乎说的是谁呢?
It's a true story. Whoabccares if it's not my story?
- 这是我的生活abc- 也是她的
- It's my life.abc- It's her life.
我死不死不是重点 她应该活下去
Point wasn't I'm dying.abcPoint was she should live.
这故事本该你来讲
You should have told her.
但你却叫她报警 寄希望于DNA标记
Instead you tell her to call theabccops, give her stats on dna markers.
死板透顶 一点也不人性化
Everything's by the book.abcNothing's ever personal.
有人要睡觉呢!
Trying to sleep here!
活检证实是急性早幼粒细胞性白血病abc 她需要骨髓移植
Biopsy confirmed apl. Sheabcneedsa bone marrow transplant.
去骨髓库找吧 我要回家
Run the donor banks. I'm going home.
我们得找到她父母
We need to track down her parents.
我猜她否定了这个提议
I assume she's alreadyabcsaid noto that idea,
不然的话 何必鼓足勇气才敢说
or there'd be no need to screwabcup your courage before saying it.
心灵有创伤的孩子无法正常思考
Children who've beenabcthrough trauma can't think clearly.
心灵有创伤 还快要死了的孩子--
Children who've beenabcthrough trauma and are dying--
看来只有我还在意病人的权利
guess I'm the only one whoabccares about patient rights.
她的选择会害死她自己
What she wants could kill her.
她真正需要的 才能挽救她
What she needs could save her.
我们的工作是找到病因abc不是治愈他们的慢性愚昧
Our job is to find out what's killingabcpatients, not treat them for chronic idiocy.
愚昧才是她的症结
Idiocy is what's killing her.
这我们可治不了 我要回家了
And since we can't cureabcthat,I'm going home.
我们能救活这病人 但你abc只想着找到自己的答案
We could save this patient, but allabcyou care about is getting your answer.
此话怎讲?
Your point being?
让Taub和Kutner去查骨髓库吧abc我要去找她的父母
Taub and kutner can check the donorabcbanks. I'm gonna find her parents.
有什么好奇怪的
Can't see why you're surprised.
你越紧逼House 他就越逆反
You push againstabchouse,he's gonna push back.
跟我过不去 我能忍
Against me,I get.
他的自负会害死我的病人
His ego's killing my patient.
你在乎这个病例是因为abc他不能干预你
You liked this ase because heabcwasn't looming over you.
你能自己拿主意
The decisions were yours.
现在只有一点不同 他决定不插手了
Only difference nowabcishe decided not to loom.
你的病人还是会死
Doesn't change the fact thatabcyour patient's dying.
我们漏掉了什么? 档案里没有的?
What are we missing?abcWhat's not in the file?
他母亲负担过重 穷途末路
The mother, over burdened atabcthe end of her rope.
把孩子弄出点病 让别人照顾他
Makes her kid sick so someoneabcelse will take care of him.
对她表示同情
Sympathize with her.
监护人佯病症?
Munchausen by proxy?
是她带他来看医生的 孩子心跳骤停时abc她也在场
She brought him into the clinic, wasabcwith him when he went into cardiac arrest.
他哥哥会察觉到 会说的
The brother would haveabcnoticed, said something.
Evan比他妈妈保护欲还强
Evan's even more protective than she is.
也许是哥哥
Then maybe it's the brother.
他才八岁
He's eight.
可能是嫉妒
Could be jealous.
恰恰相反
He's the opposite of jealous.
他干什么都惦记着Jonah
He includes jonah in everything he does.
确保他吃了饭 给他刷牙
Makes sure he eats,brushes his teeth.
我觉得 我们给了他灵感
I think we gave him an idea.
要不然就是去追杀House了
Either that or he's off to kill house.
- Velez先生?abc- 什么事?
- Mr. Velez?abc- Yeah?
我是Remy Hadley医生abc在Princeton-Plainsboro 医院工作
I'm dr. Remy hadleyabcfrom princeton-plainsboro hospital.
你女儿Sophia被确诊为白血病
We're treating your daughterabcsophia for leukemia
我们想为你和你妻子abc做个骨髓移植测试
and we need to test both you andabcyour wife for bone marrow donation.
等等abc你说你是Princeton-Plainsboro医院的?
I'm sorry, you said you wereabcfrom princeton-plainsboro?
我知道有些突然 但时间紧迫--
I know this is uneected,butabctime is short and--
出了什么事?
what's going on?
这医生说你得了白血病
This doctor says you have leukemia.
我没得白血病
I don't have leukemia.
- 你是Sophia Velez?abc- 怎么?
- Sophia velez?abc- Yeah?
- Sophia Isabel Velez?abc- 是我啊
- Sophia isabel velez?abc- Yeah.
你有事要告诉我么?
Do you know something I don't?
是骗子就会撒谎
Just that liars lie.
你冒充了她的身份
you stole her identity.
这是自我保护
To protect myself.
这样他们才找不到我
So they can't find me.
我们可以保护你
We can protect you.
但我们得找到你父母
But we need to find your parents.
为什么?
Why?
你们取了我的血 不需要我的名字abc也能找到供体
You have my blood. You don'tabcneed my name to find a donor.
你是未成年人
You're a minor.
你肯定伪造了脱离监管协议
You obviously forged theabcemancipation papers.
即使找到供体 手术也要你父母同意
Even if we had a donor, we'd stillabcneed your parents' consent to treat you.
你就不能假装没去拜访么?
Can't you just pretend youabcdidn't go to that house?
假装没见过那女孩
That you didn't find that girl?
联系你父母不代表你们要团聚
Calling your parents doesn'tabcmean a family reunion.
甚至不需要见他们
You don't even have to see them.
等我病得再重些 情况紧急了
When I get sickabcenough,it'll be an emergency.
你们就不得不给我移植
You'll have to give me a transplant.
即使没经过父母同意
Even without consent.
铁摄入过量?
an iron overdose?
维生素片里的
From his vitamins.
如果没错 今晚就可以开始治疗
If I'm right, we can treat him tonight.
明天一早他就能康复
He'll be back to hisabcold self in the morning.
但是...
But...
这是儿童维生素片 我--我只给了他一片
they're children's vitamins.abcI--I only give him one.
我知道
I know.
我以为多吃点 他就能更强壮
I thought more would make him strong.
我不是有意让他生病的
I didn't mean to make him sick.
他会好起来的
He's gonna be okay.
他会恨我
He's gonna hate me.
手足之情是很奇妙的
Well, that's the greatabcthing about brothers.
你犯了错误 但他们仍然爱你
You can make mistakes,andabcthey'll still love you.
骨髓库里只有不完全匹配的样本
Donor list turned up a partial match.
给她用吧
So treat her.
匹配度只有一半
It's only a three out of six.
那就别给她用
So don't treat her.
她恐怕撑不过这个星期
She may not last the week.
一半匹配总比没有好
Partial's better than nothing.
- 那就给她用吧abc- 会有排异反应的
- So treat her.abc- She'll reject it.
她会很虚弱 即使有更好的供体abc她也无法进行第二次手术
And she'll be too weak to tryabcagain when a better match turns up.
该我说话了 是不?
It's my turn now,right?
前提是 还有更好的供体
If a better match turns up.
等你们决定了 再来找我
Well, when you decide,get back to me.
她很害怕
She's scared.
明显还怕得不够
Not scared enough.
跟她说 情绪反应是很不理性的
Tell her the thing about emotional reactionsabcis they're definitionally irrational.
或者说 是愚蠢的
Or stupid.
你习惯怎么说都行
Might wanna phraseabcthat in your own words.
她不想让父母因为abc救了她的命而感到欣慰
She wants to deny her parents theabcsatisfaction of saving her life.
那是你对她的情绪反应abc做出的理性解释
That's your rational explanation ofabcher emotional response.
这就是她的解释
That was her explanation.
挺合理的么
That makes sense.
她过了多久才这么说的?
How long did it takeabcher to come up with that?
几乎是立马
It was her immediate reaction.
这就没道理了
That doesn't make sense.
解释很合理 却反而说不通了?
The fact that it makesabcsense doesn't make sense?
情绪是即刻的
Emotional is immediate.
她一下就这么理智
She went to rational first.
说明压根没有牵扯到感情
Means there was no emotional to process.
你是说 她说被强奸是撒谎了?
You're saying she'sabclying about being raped?
也不是她第一次了
Wouldn't be her first.
她是以此为借口 掩饰更深的创伤
She lied about one trauma toabccover a worse trauma.
那么 还有什么比强奸更糟呢?
So... what's worse than rape?
嗨 我是House医生
Hi, I'm dr. House.
你到底做了什么啊?
What did you do?
- 我没...abc- 肯定有事发生过 但不是强奸
- I don't-- - somethingabchappened,but it wasn't rape.
信不信由你
Believe whatever you want.
你很恐慌 顽固 还不让别人同情你
You're scared,and stubborn, and youabcdon't like people feeling sorry for you.
为什么不让?
Why not?
我不要人怜悯
I don't want pity.
我只想过正常的生活
I just wanna be normal.
但你知道你做不到
But you know you're not.
你要别人看到你很独立 应付得很好
You need people to see how independentabcyou are, how well you're coping.
这样他们就看不到你abc遍体鳞伤 不知所措
So they won't see theabclost,hurt little girl.
因为你不这么看
Because that's not what you see.
你只看到你犯下的大错...
You see someone who didabcsomething terrible...
活该因此忍受痛苦
who deserves to suffer.
不配继续活下去
Who doesn't deserve to live.
你究竟做了什么?
What did you do?
我们终究会找到你的父母...
Eventually,we'll find your parents...
就算是仅仅为了送回遗体
if only to deliver the body.
他们不会在乎的
Then they won't care.
你真白痴
You're an idiot.
你宁可去死都不愿面对你父母abc就因为个啥? 你把法贝蛋雕摔破了?
You'd rather die than face your parentsabcbecause, what,you broke their faberge egg?
我害死了他们的儿子
I killed their son.
我害死了我弟弟
I killed my brother.
我本该看好他的
I was supposed to watch him.
当时他在洗澡
He was in the bath.
我还能听见他在笑
I could hear him laughing.
他们每看我一眼 感觉abc就好像我又害死他一次
Every time they look atabcme,it's like I kill him again.
如果你不接受父母的骨髓...
If you don't take yourabcparents' bone marrow...
你就会害死他们的另一个孩子
you'd be killing their other child.
即使他们现在不恨你 那时也会的
If they don't hateabcyou now,they will then.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你当然在乎
Sure you do.
你需要有人告诉你 那只是个意外
You want someone to tellabcyouit was just an accident.
没那么糟糕 但事已至此
That it's not thatabcbad,but it is that bad.
你自己很清楚
And you know it.
你无法改变这现实
There's nothing youabccan doto change that.
但你可以 不让它变得更糟
But there is one thing you canabcdo to not make it worse.
* 有没有人 *
* Someone *
* 把我寻找 *
* reaching for me now *
* 穿越黑暗 *
* through the dark *
* 追寻着我 *
* reaching for me now *
* 需要 有一个人 *
* you need someone *
* 听见 你的叹息 *
* to hear you when you sigh *
* 能否有人 *
* someone *
* 为你拭去 脸旁泪水 *
* to wipe away those tears you cried *
* 有人 给你拥抱 *
* someone to hold *
* 黑夜之下 *
* you 'neath the darkened sky *
* 是否有人 *
* someone *
* 比我 爱你更深 *
* to love you more than I *
你要是想来庆祝那孩子骨髓移植成功abc你就来晚了
if you're here to celebrate the kid's boneabcmarrow transplant working, you missed cake.
我要做临床试验
I want to do clinical trials.
这事早就谈过了
Already had this conversation.
我已证明了自己可以abc同时处理两个病例
I've proved that I canabcwork two cases at once.
我能做到 我就要这么做
I can do this. And I'm doing it.
好吧
Okay.
好吧? 就这样?
Okay? Just like that?
能晚点再告诉你原因么?abc... 或者永不再提?
Can I give my reasons later... or never?
三天前你还说不行呢
Three days ago you said no.
三天前你是来问我
Three days ago you asked me.
现在你只是来告诉我
Now you told me.
不是个问题 就没法说不啊
Can't say no if it's not a question.
你为Foreman做了件好事
Nice thing you did for foreman.
他真是个大嘴巴
He speaks.
他懂得变通
He deflects.
我差点让个四岁小孩丢了性命
I almost costaabcfour-year-old his life.
你知道Foreman能解决的
Well, you knewabcforeman would figure it out.
我哪知道?
Did I?
你就是要他证明自己
You just needed to prove it to him.
你真混账
You're an ass.
但也很高尚
But a noble one.
你是夸我聪明吧
I sound clever.
谢谢你理解
Thank you.
你那小把戏不管用
Your little game didn't work.
我不是Foreman 你也不是我
I'm not foreman,and you're not me.
要聊聊她么?
you wanna talk about her?
- 不要abc- 好吧
- Nope.abc- All right.
你会好起来的 House
You're gonna be okay,house.
知道这真好
Good to know.